

I am a motivated and knowledgeable visual designer with experience in creating and producing a wide range projects. With my education in tech and my work as print/web designer, I have the unique skill set to create human-friendly digital solutions. I am tireless in my desire to learn and improve on what I already know.

EXPERIENCE

Visual Designer

BlueApple Design, Menlo Park, CA

Apr 2016-Present

 Created digital banners, icons, designed and laid out interactive e-books and whitepapers by following corporate brand identity and visual guidelines

Visual Designer

Safe Drive Systems, New York, NY

Mar 2015-Mar 2016

- Designed user-centered landing pages, banner ads, e-brochures, and flyers from design concept to completion
- Created animated presentations in Keynote and PowerPoint for potential car buyers in 60+ dealerships and product promotion on company website
- Redesigned website blog for better user interaction and SEO optimization; blog traffic increased by over 50%

Graphic Designer

IMR, New York, NY

Sept 2014-Aug 2015

- Supervised redesign, layout, and production of "IMR Review," the quarterly corporate magazine with circulation of TK
- Implemented image manipulations, color correction, photo retouching, and vector graphics to improve visual perception and quality of the magazine
- Designed, laid out, and produced multi-page journalistic reports from initial concept through prepress under tight deadlines with no errors; successfully presented at a conference in Washington, D.C., and at a political discussion forum in NYC

Sr. Graphic/Web Designer

Integral LLC, Yekaterinburg, Russia

Dec 2000-May 2014

- Supervised design, layout and production of 5 monthly scientificpractical magazines and 3 monthly newspapers
- Designed, laid out, and produced creative materials including ads, posters, newsletters, printed brochures, booklets with vector diagrams and infographics, digital banners, and presentations
- Collaborated with marketing team and developers to redesign clients' websites to provide more efficient experience for users
- Reduced ~30% of client printing costs by interviewing and selecting the best offset/digital print vendor

- http://bolshchikova.com
- olga.bolshchikova@gmail.com
- **347) 873-7216**
- San Jose, CA

SKILLS

UX Design

- User research
- Information Architecture
- Wireframing
- Interactive prototyping
- Usability testing

Visual design

- Responsive design
- Web / Print design / Layout
- Typography
- Photo retouching
- Full print production

TOOLS

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Muse
- Adobe Acrobat Pro
- Sketch
- InVision
- Balsamiq
- HTML5 / CSS3
- Keynote / PowerPoint
- Common sense

EDUCATION

 UX: Research & Strategy, Interaction Design

DesignLab Feb 2017

UX/UI Design Fundamentals

Bloc.io Dec 2015

 Bachelor of Science (BS), Engineering Physics

Ural Federal University, Russia

TRAINING

• UX & Web Design Master Course: Strategy, Design, Development Udemy March 2017

• Human-Computer Interaction
Coursera Aug 2014

HTML & CSS

Codecademy May 2013